♪Menelan kegelisahan♪
♪梅内兰·凯格利萨汉♪
♪Your roots firmly grip this land♪
♪你的根牢牢扎牢这片土地♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪门格贾尔·姆巴克♪
♪My leaves cross a distant border♪
♪我的叶子 跨越遥远的国界♪
♪Kejauhan Menants♪
♪Kejauhan Menants♪
♪Eternity is the ultimate goal♪
♪永恒是终极目标♪
♪Separating again after meeting♪
♪相遇又分离♪
♪Back apart after leaning in♪
♪倾身后退一步♪
♪I never forget♪
♪我永远不会忘记♪
♪A sword flash splits the colored sky♪
♪剑光 撕裂彩色天空♪
♪Abandoned dreams shattered♪
♪被遗弃的梦想 破灭了♪
♪Breaking through fearlessly♪
♪无畏地突破♪
♪Looking at the waves of the anchored sails, the world has changed♪
♪看着停泊的风帆的波浪， 世界已经改变了♪
♪Armor and makeup scattered in the air♪
♪铠甲和妆容散落在空中♪
♪Ever scared, the blood doesn't dry up, and dreaming of twilight♪
♪一直害怕，血不干涸， 梦到黄昏♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪只希望你在我身边♪
♪Youth is not wasted♪
♪青春不虚度♪
♪Stand firm, unite with each other, and raise your sword with you♪
♪坚定立场，团结一致， 一起举剑♪
♪Seeing sparks fall on our shoulders♪
♪看到火花 落在我们的肩上♪
♪There are no regrets in this mortal world♪
♪人间无悔♪
=Love Trip=
=爱情之旅=
=Episode 19=
=第19集=
Don't worry, Dad.
别担心，爸爸。
Ananda has prepared a fast horse.
阿难准备了一匹快马。
If the war situation is unfavorable,
如果战局 不利，
Ananda will definitely accompany your father's retreat to the south.
阿难一定会陪你父亲 南渡的。
As long as entering the banks of the Jiangnan River, with the natural dangers there,
只要进入江南江边， 那里的天险，
we will definitely be fine.
我们一定会没事的。
Father, if the war situation is unfavorable,
父亲，如果战局 不利，
Ananda is willing to stay here
阿难愿意留在这里
lead the rearguard to block the enemy's forces.
率领后卫 阻挡敌军。
At that time, please go first with your father.
到时候，请你 先和你父亲一起去吧。
Second Sister,
二姐，
Your loyalty and courage are truly commendable.
你们的忠诚和勇气 确实值得称赞。
Brother is the eldest son.
哥哥是长子。
In the future, this country and your father will have to rely on Big Brother.
以后这个国家、你的父亲 都得靠老大哥了。
If I could stay here to intercept the enemy forces
如果我能留在这里 拦截敌军
and protect the safety of your Father and Sister,
保护你父亲和妹妹的安全，
even if I die, that is also worth it.
就算我死了，那也是值得的。
Lai'er is really a good, filial child.
来儿真是 一个孝顺的好孩子。
Second Sister.
二姐。
Second Sister, you can't...
二姐，你不能……
His Majesty!
陛下！
Report, Your Majesty!
报告陛下！
There's news from the front lines!
前线传来消息！
Say it quickly!
快点说吧！
King Qin has captured West Changjing.
秦王攻占了 西长靖。
Congratulations, His Majesty.
恭喜陛下。
King Qin defeats Sun Jing
秦王击败孙敬
and had charged into West Changjing with his troops.
并率军冲入西长泾。
What?
什么？
- Congratulations, Father!
- 恭喜你，父亲！
Your father is protected and blessed by Heaven
你的父亲受到上天的保护和祝福
so that the new King of Qin could retake West Changjing!
让新秦王能够 夺回西长靖！
Congratulations, Dad!
恭喜你，爸爸！
His father placed King Qin in an important position
他的父亲重用秦王
so that the new King of Qin could retake West Changjing!
让新秦王能够 夺回西长靖！
Your father looks far ahead
你的父亲目光长远
and this is a blessing for this country!
这是 这个国家的福气！
Good! Very good!
好的！非常好！
Counselor Wu's words were true.
吴参赞说得确实。
I am destined to be emperor.
我注定要成为皇帝。
As long as I ascend the throne as emperor,
只要我登基为皇帝，
all the people in this country will be saved.
这个国家的所有人民都 将得救。
- Congratulations, Father! - Congratulations, Your Majesty!
- 恭喜你，父亲！ - 恭喜您，陛下！
(Istana Chaoqian)
(Istana Chaoqian)
That year, when he was 16 years old,
那一年，他16岁，
according to tradition, I must enter the palace
按照传统， 我必须进宫
to bid farewell to the Former Emperor
告别 先皇
before leaving for Laolan Border.
然后前往老兰边境。
At that time, I made a mistake.
那时，我犯了一个错误。
The Former Emperor was furious
前皇帝勃然大怒
and not willing to meet me.
并且不愿意见到我。
He sent someone to convey a message to me
他派人 给我传达消息
so that I am satisfied with my fate, do my duty,
这样我就满足于我的命运， 尽我的责任，
and stop tarnishing the reputation of the descendants of the Li Family.
别再玷污 李家子孙的名声了。
His Majesty has now reclaimed West Changjing.
陛下现已收复 西长靖。
This will comfort the soul of the Past Emperor in heaven.
这样才能安抚 天上先帝的灵魂。
What about the person chasing Sun Jing?
那 追孙静的人呢？
After several times of close combat,
经过数次 近战，
we still can't hold them.
我们仍然无法控制它们。
Sun Jing's trusted deputy general protected him tooth and nail.
孙敬最信任的副将 竭尽全力保护他。
Sun Jing should still be unconscious now.
孙静 现在应该还昏迷不醒。
They fought while retreating
他们一边撤退一边战斗
and had also retreated all the way to the Tong Border that night.
并于当晚一路撤退 至潼境。
What about Great General Cui?
崔大将军呢？
After capturing the city,
攻占城市后，
Great General Cui led troops into the palace,
崔大将军率兵 入宫，
then got off the horse in front of Jianyuan Hall
然后在建元殿前下马
and entered Yunxiao Terrace from the back.
从后面进入了云霄台。
He said one sentence, "My enthusiasm has faded, that's all",
他说了一句话， “我的热情消退了，仅此而已”，
then led the troops out of the palace
然后率领部队 出了皇宫
and headed for the Cui Family Army headquarters outside the city.
前往城外的崔家军总部。
"Just that".
“只是”。
I also want to be the same as him, after capturing the city and killing the enemy,
我也想和他一样， 攻下城池，杀掉敌人后，
then finally said "that's it" and left.
然后最后说“就这样” 然后离开了。
That was the style of a true general.
这才是真正的将军的作风。
Honourable,
尊敬的，
You and him are not the same.
你和他不一样。
However, I am currently very jealous of him.
不过，我现在 很嫉妒他。
His Majesty came out of Laolan Border,
陛下 从老兰边境出来，
leads an army to rescue the emperor and quell the rebellion.
率军救援 皇帝，平定叛乱。
Now, you have reclaimed West Changjing.
现在，你已经收复了 西长靖。
So, from now on, you are different from everyone.
所以，从现在开始， 你就和大家不一样了。
You also can no longer say you are jealous of other people.
你也不能再说 你嫉妒别人。
That's right, it's really boring.
没错，确实很无聊。
Di mana Ying?
Di mana Ying?
Was he out of town with Great General Cui?
他是跟崔大将军一起出城的吗？
It turns out this is the royal palace.
原来这里是皇宫。
Commander,
指挥官，
here besides the building is a little taller
这里除了 建筑物有点高之外
and the house is a little bigger, nothing seems different.
而且房子大了一点， 看起来没什么不同。
Look at it.
看它。
Where we live now
我们现在住的地方
named Yuhui Pavilion.
名玉惠阁。
Ahead is the Jianyuan Hall,
前面是建元殿，
Aula Qianzheng,
Aula Qianzheng,
dan Aula Jingde.
dan Aula Jingde.
These were all the places of the emperors of previous dynasties
这些都是历代皇帝的地方
take care of governance.
抓好治理。
Behind the high wall is the Palace of the Crown Prince,
高墙后面 是太子殿，
which borders this Yuhui Pavilion.
与这座御惠阁接壤 。
Further back is the harem palace.
再往后 就是后宫。
How many people can live in such a big house?
这么大的房子能住几个人？
The emperor had dozens of sons and hundreds of grandchildren.
皇帝有数十个儿子 和数百个孙子。
There are many descendants.
子孙众多。
If the palace does not fit, the respective kings will be given
如果宫殿不合适， 将给予相应的国王
residence outside the palace to live in after marriage.
婚后在宫外居住的住所。
Sadly,
可悲的是，
Sun Jing rebelled
孙敬叛乱
and wiped out almost all of the descendants of the Li Family.
并把李家的子孙几乎全部消灭了。
King Qin came.
秦王来了。
Ying,
英，
I want to ask for your help on one thing.
我想请你帮忙 做一件事。
Which matter?
哪个重要？
The Previous Crown Princess, Madam Xiao,
前任太子妃萧氏，
has endured humiliation and carried heavy burdens.
受尽屈辱 ，背负重担。
For the sake of poisoning Sun Jing, he himself was also poisoned
为了毒死孙靖， 他自己也被毒死
and now his life is in danger.
现在他的生命处于危险之中。
I want to ask Taozi to treat him.
我想请桃子给他治病。
Because I'm not free,
因为我不自由，
please replace me to take care of him.
请代替我 来照顾他。
It turns out he was the one who poisoned Sun Jing.
原来他就是对孙靖下毒的人。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
For someone who upholds justice so much,
对于一个如此维护正义的人来说，
I will definitely not disappoint you.
我绝对不会让你失望的。
This lip color box is the poison.
这个唇彩盒就是毒药。
Madam said,
女士说，
if he poisons food,
如果他在食物中投毒
afraid that Sun Jing would notice.
生怕被孙静发现。
So, he put poison in the lip color.
于是，他 在唇彩里下了毒。
Madam also said that this poison has a sweet aroma
夫人还说， 此毒有甜香。
and only the floral scent of the lip color can mask the scent.
而只有唇色的花香 才能掩盖香味。
Besides, there is only one chance.
更何况，机会只有 一次。
On the day the city was attacked,
攻城那天，
he immediately smeared the poison on his own lips
他立即将毒药涂 在自己的嘴唇上
without caring at all, this poison will also attack his heart.
毫不在意，这种毒 也会侵袭他的心脏。
Mrs
太太
was determined to die with him.
决心与他同归于尽。
(Luoyang)
（洛阳）
- Greetings to your father.
- 向你父亲问好。
No need to be formal.
不需要很正式。
- Thank you, Father.
- 谢谢你，父亲。
The King of Qin sent an army outside the city to welcome.
秦王派大军 出城迎接。
As emperor,
作为皇帝，
I must appear grand when I return to West Changjing
我回西长靖一定要盛装打扮
to receive congratulations from the officials.
接受 官员的祝贺。
Father, there are several things
父亲，有几件事
which I don't know if I should say it or not.
我不知道是否应该 说。
You don't need to hesitate. Say.
您无需犹豫。说。
Now King Qin has reclaimed West Changjing
现在秦王收复了 西长靖
and make unmatched contributions.
并做出了 无与伦比的贡献。
How will your father reward the King of Qin?
你的父亲会怎样奖赏 秦王呢？
This...
这...
He is my son.
他是我的儿子。
After all, isn't sharing his father's burden
毕竟，不是在 分担父亲的负担
is it an obligation?
这是一种义务吗？
Why should you be rewarded?
为什么你应该得到奖励？
Your father has crowned the Third Brother as the King of Qin.
你父亲已封 三弟为秦王。
Among the kings, only the title of King of Qin is the highest.
诸王之中， 只有秦王的称号是最高的。
If rewarded again,
如果再有奖励的话
he could only be crowned Crown Prince.
他只能被加冕 为太子。
You said you appointed him Crown Prince?
你说你立他 为太子？
By direct line of descent, he has no rights.
由于直系血统， 他没有任何权利。
Tell me, why should he be appointed Crown Prince?
你告诉我，为什么要 立他为太子？
If at this time your father
如果此时你的父亲
did not intend to appoint the Third Brother as Crown Prince
无意立三弟 为太子
while he is not rewarded
虽然他没有得到奖励
even though he has made a great contribution,
尽管他做出了巨大的贡献，
afraid that there would be people with ulterior motives
怕有人 别有用心
which incites the three forces to rebel
煽动三大势力 造反
and the situation will be serious.
情况将会很严重。
This is... rebellion?
这是……叛逆？
This...
这...
Don't panic, Dad.
别惊慌，爸爸。
After returning to the palace,
回到皇宫后，
Your father can open the palace treasury.
你父亲可以打开 宫库。
It is said that Sun Jing left in a hurry
据说孙静走的 很匆忙
and do not bring valuables that are in the palace treasury.
请勿携带 宫库内的贵重物品。
Treasury?
国库？
Right, your father.
对了，你的父亲。
What if your father opened the palace treasury
如果你父亲 打开了宫库怎么办
and provide rewards
并提供奖励
to the soldiers who reclaimed West Changjing?
收复西长靖的将士 ？
The soldiers will surely be grateful for His Majesty's gift.
士兵们一定会 感激陛下的礼物。
Even if someone incites, they will not join in making trouble.
即使有人煽动， 他们也不会加入闹事。
Jun'er and Lai'er's methods are indeed good.
君儿和来儿的手段确实不错。
Once I return to West Changjing, I will open the palace treasury
等我回到西长靖， 我就打开宫库
and give rewards to all three teams.
并对三支队伍给予奖励。
His Majesty's goodness is great, beneficial for the country forever.
陛下的恩德很大， 对国家永远有利。
Long live forever!
万岁万岁！
(Chaoqian Palace) His Majesty's virtue is great,
（朝前宫） 陛下德行伟大，
beneficial to the country forever.
对国家永远有利。
Long live forever!
万岁万岁！
Mrs.
太太。
Madam, are you awake?
女士，您醒了吗？
Madam, you are awake.
夫人，您醒了。
It's good to be aware.
意识到这一点是件好事。
That means the effects of the poison have subsided.
这意味着毒药的影响已经减弱。
Long live His Majesty!
陛下万岁！
Outside...
外部...
What's that sound outside?
外面是什么声音？
Mrs,
太太，
You've been unconscious for days.
你已经昏迷了 好几天了。
By leading the Western Border Army,
率领 西部边防军，
His Majesty the King of Qin has reclaimed West Changjing,
秦王陛下 收复了西长靖，
then welcomed His Majesty back to the palace.
随后迎接陛下 回宫。
Today,
今天，
He received congratulations from the officials.
他收到了 官员们的祝贺。
That voice outside
外面那个声音
was the grateful voice of the third team.
这是 第三队感激的声音。
We... we won.
我们……我们赢了。
Be careful, madam.
小心点，女士。
We won.
我们赢了。
Don't worry, madam.
别担心，女士。
Who are these two ladies?
这两位女士是谁？
Madam, this is Commander He of the Cui Family Army.
夫人，这位是 崔家军的何司令。
He was asked by King Qin to come and treat his Lady.
他奉秦王之命 前来为夫人治病。
Thanks to Miss Taozi brought by Commander He,
感谢 何司令带来的桃子小姐，
who dispenses medicine carefully every day,
每天精心配药，
The poison in Madam finally disappeared.
夫人体内的毒终于消失了。
Thank you, Commander He.
谢谢何司令。
Madam upholds justice
夫人主持正义
and save everyone in this country.
并拯救 这个国家的所有人。
I should be the one thanking Madam
我应该是 感谢女士的人
represents everyone in this country.
代表这个国家的每个人。
I don't deserve Madam's thanks.
我不值得 夫人的感谢。
This palace is not bad.
这个宫殿还不错。
It's just that these curtains are a bit worn.
只是这些窗帘有点破旧了。
Replace everything with new ones.
把所有东西都换成新的。
Good.
好的。
Greetings to your father.
向你父亲问好。
No need to be formal.
不需要很正式。
King Qin, what a coincidence you came.
秦王，你来得真巧。
This time, you made a huge contribution in reclaiming West Changjing.
这次，你 为收复西长靖做出了巨大的贡献。
Say, what gift do you want?
说吧， 你想要什么礼物？
Gold and silver or fiefdoms?
金银还是封地？
His Majesty,
陛下，
Ananda did not want any gifts.
阿难并不想要 任何礼物。
Ananda wants to ask for orders.
阿难欲请教。
After Ananda sent people to find the Emperor's First Grandson,
阿难派人 寻找皇长孙后，
please His Majesty agree to welcome back the Emperor's First Grandson.
请陛下同意迎 回皇长孙。
The Emperor's First Grandson?
皇帝的长孙？
When Sun Jing rebelled,
孙敬叛乱时，
he killed the First Emperor and the First Crown Prince.
他杀了始皇 和太子。
Fortunately Han Chang, General Yunchang,
Fortunately Han Chang, General Yunchang,
protect the Emperor's First Grandson to escape.
保护皇长孙 逃脱。
His Majesty,
陛下，
The Emperor's First Grandson
皇帝的长孙
is a direct descendant of the First Emperor.
是始皇的嫡系后裔。
Please His Majesty agree to welcome back the Emperor's First Grandson
请陛下同意迎 回皇长孙
and set him as the crown prince.
并立他为太子。
This is a big problem, I have to consider it first.
这是一个大问题， 我得先考虑一下。
His Majesty, the First Emperor passed away
始皇帝陛下去世
and the Former Crown Prince sacrificed for the country.
前皇太子 为国家牺牲。
The Emperor's First Grandson inheriting the throne was a matter of course.
皇长孙继承皇位 是理所当然的事。
I told you I would consider it first.
我告诉过你我会 先考虑一下。
Go home first.
先回家吧。
You've been quite busy lately.
你最近很忙。
Go home and rest.
回家休息。
If there is no need, do not enter the palace first.
若无必要， 请勿先入宫。
Good.
好的。
Mrs,
太太，
eat again
再吃一次
Bibi Jin,
比比金,
is Sun Jing still alive?
孙静还活着吗？
Mrs.
太太。
Correct.
正确的。
Logically,
从逻辑上讲，
I should be worried
我应该担心
because of this big threat
因为这个巨大的威胁
still not removed.
仍然没有删除。
However, when I remember
然而，当我想起
how he rushed to the palace covered in blood
他是如何浑身是血冲进皇宫的
and hold my hand...
并握住我的手...
What was I thinking at that time?
我当时在想什么？
I am the First Crown Princess.
我是第一太子妃。
Mrs.
太太。
During the days I spent in the Crown Prince's Palace,
我在太子殿度过的那些日子，
I'm alive,
我还活着，
but like an empty shell.
但就像一个空壳。
Only when I'm with him,
只有和他在一起的时候，
I feel like I really am a human being.
我觉得我真的 是一个人。
However, I am the First Crown Princess.
不过，我是 第一太子妃。
I'm not supposed to like it.
我不应该喜欢它。
Mrs.
太太。
I know.
我知道。
I won't discuss it any more.
我不会再讨论它了。
No one will ever know
没有人会知道
the past between me and him,
我和他之间的过去
Nor will anyone else know who I am now
别人也不会知道 我现在是谁
still love her.
仍然爱她。
Mrs.
太太。
My relationship with Sun Jing
我和孙静的关系
insincere and full of hypocrisy.
不真诚且充满虚伪。
I've lost my reputation.
我已经失去了名誉。
It wouldn't be a pity if I died.
如果我死了也不可惜。
Mrs,
太太，
You can't say that.
你不能这么说。
Stay cool,
保持冷静，
I won't die now.
我现在不会死。
I still have to confirm that the Emperor's First Grandson
我还得确认 一下皇长孙
come back safely.
安全回来。
I want to see it
我想看一看
grow up well.
好好成长。
At the time,
当时，
I'll just be able to go to the afterlife
我只能去往来世
to meet the Former Crown Prince.
去见前皇太子。
Mrs.
太太。
Don't.
不。
(Residence of the King of Qin)
（秦王府）
(Legenda Jiang Ziya)
(Legenda Jiang Ziya)
Are you still willing to come visit me?
你还愿意来看我吗？
I thought Big Miss Cui had forgotten about me a long time ago.
我以为崔大小姐 早就忘记我了。
Why is His Highness the King of Qin so forgetful?
秦王殿下为何 如此健忘？
It was clearly His Majesty King Qin who asked me to take care of Madam Xiao.
分明是秦王陛下 让我照顾萧夫人的。
Mrs. Xiao's health has improved a lot today.
今天肖太太的身体状况 好多了。
He could already talk after eating a bowl of porridge.
喝完一碗粥，他已经能说话了。
So, I just had time to leave the palace and visit you.
所以，我刚好有时间离开皇宫 ，来看望你。
I went straight to you without having time to visit my father,
我没有时间去拜访我的父亲，就直接去找你了，
but you don't appreciate it. If that's the case, I'll just go.
但你不欣赏它。 既然如此，那我就走了。
I want to go out of town to meet my father.
我想要出城 去见我的父亲。
(Broad and Open Minded) I'm just kidding.
（思想开放） 我只是开玩笑。
That's all, accompany me for a moment.
就这样吧，陪我一会儿吧。
Later I will go out of town with you
稍后我会和你一起出城
to visit Great General Cui. How?
拜访 崔大将军。如何？
You're not afraid that my father will tie you up again
你就不怕我爸 再把你绑起来
and put you in a box?
然后把你放进盒子里？
You will definitely save me.
你一定会救我的。
That's not necessarily true.
这不一定是真的。
What's wrong with you?
你这人怎么回事？
Is there anything that makes you unhappy?
有什么事情让你 不开心吗？
Otherwise, why are you lying here alone?
不然你怎么 一个人躺在这里？
No, I read books because I'm bored,
不，我看书是因为我无聊
then almost fell asleep because he was so bored.
然后因为太无聊了，差点就睡着了。
I heard His Majesty opening the palace treasury
我听见陛下打开 宫库的声音
and use its contents to reward all three teams.
并用它的内容来奖励 所有三个团队。
Logically speaking, you have made a great contribution,
按理来说，你做出了很大的贡献，
So the King of Qin's Residence should have many guests.
所以说秦王府的 客人应该是很多的。
Why so quiet and lonely?
为什么如此安静和孤独？
I don't like those civil officials.
我不喜欢那些文官。
After all, I am the King of Qin who leads the Western Border Army.
我毕竟是统领西边军的秦王。
I am not free to make friends with civil officials.
我无权 与文官交朋友。
If I were friends with the general,
如果我和将军是朋友
it will arouse suspicion and be easily misunderstood.
会引起怀疑 ，容易被误解。
So, I thought
所以我认为
to refuse guests.
来拒绝客人。
Civil and military officials also know my nature
文武百官 亦知我性
so did not dare to come.
所以没敢来。
It's okay if it's someone else.
如果是别人也没关系。
However, shouldn't you visit Prime Minister Gu?
不过，你不是应该 去拜访顾总理吗？
During the day at the palace meeting, the position of Prime Minister Gu was restored.
白天的宫会上， 顾相的位置被恢复了。
His Majesty wanted to give him the title,
陛下想赐他爵位，
but Prime Minister Gu knelt down to thank him and refused.
但顾丞相跪拜 谢意，不肯。
He is amazing.
他很棒。
He also helped a lot in reclaiming West Changjing.
他还为收复西长靖做出了很大的贡献。
So, after the palace meeting that day,
所以，那天宫会之后，
I went to Prime Minister Gu's Residence and thanked him.
我到顾总理官邸向 他表示感谢。
You just visit and thank you?
你只是来拜访 并表示感谢吗？
Then... He didn't even want a reward from His Majesty,
那么……他连陛下的赏赐都不要了，
what else can I do?
我还可以做些什么？
Since you already went to the Gu Residence, didn't you meet Gu Wanniang?
你既然去了顾府， 没见过顾万娘吗？
(Broad and Open Minded)
（心胸宽广、开放）
Why did I see Gu Wanniang?
我为什么会看到顾万娘？
I don't care why you met him.
我不在乎 你为什么遇见他。
Ying, are you jealous?
莹，你吃醋了吗？
No.
不。
You're jealous.
你嫉妒。
Absolutely not.
绝对不。
I want to go out of town to meet my father.
我想要出城 去见我的父亲。
I'm coming so you can rest easy.
我来了，你就可以安心休息了。
No need.
不需要。
Don't be jealous anymore.
别再嫉妒了。
Ladies and Gentlemen, please have a look and take your pick.
女士们先生们， 请看一下并做出选择。
Nuts in our shop
我们店里有坚果
dense, crunchy, and the delicious taste lasts a long time in the mouth.
口感绵密、松脆，美味 在口中久久不散。
You will definitely be satisfied.
您一定会满意的。
I want a pack of everything here .
我想要一包这里所有的东西。
Please wait a moment.
请稍候。
(Wollong)
(卧龙)
At that time you said in the letter that after entering the capital,
当时你在信中说 ，进入京城后，
we have to come together to this dried fruit shop.
我们必须一起来到 这家干果店。
Today, it finally came true.
今天，它终于实现了。
I bought so much this time it's enough for you to eat for a while.
这次买了这么多， 够你吃一会儿了。
Why do you sound a bit reluctant?
为什么你听起来 有点不情愿？
I don't mind.
我不介意。
I just thought who knows when we will be able to meet again
我只是想谁知道 我们什么时候才能再次见面
after parting today.
今天分别之后。
Shiqi suddenly acted childish.
十七突然表现得很 幼稚。
That was quite surprising.
这实在是太令人惊讶了。
Initially, I wanted to buy just a little.
最初，我只想买 一点。
That way, you'll think of me whenever it's over.
这样， 每当比赛结束时，你就会想起我。
However, I then thought it would be a good idea to buy more.
然而，我后来认为 购买更多是个好主意。
That way, you'll think of me when you eat it. It is better.
这样 你吃的时候就会想起我。这个比较好。
Who will think of you when you eat dried fruit?
当你吃干果时谁会想起你？
Me.
我。
I will remember you when I eat it.
吃完我就会想起你。
However,
然而，
your favorite
你的最爱
would also be my favorite.
也会是我的最爱。
Sir, this is your dried fruit.
先生，这是您的干果。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Ayo.
阿哟。
Madam looks much better and is also more stable when walking.
夫人气色好多了 ，走路也稳了。
Miss Taozi said, as long as it is well maintained,
桃子小姐说， 只要保养得好，
Madam will be fine later.
夫人以后就好了。
Commander He arrives!
何司令来了！
Mrs.
太太。
Is Madam feeling better today?
女士 今天感觉好些了吗？
It's much better.
好多了。
Come here and sit.
过来坐吧。
Thank you Madam.
谢谢夫人。
Judging from the complexion of her face, Madam was much better.
从夫人的脸色来看， 已经好了很多。
Taozi told me that Madam's body would be very weak
桃子告诉我 ，夫人的身体会很虚弱
after the poison is gone
毒消失后
and need to consume snow ginseng to improve health.
并且需要食用雪参 来改善健康。
I told King Qin about this.
我把这件事告诉了秦王。
Then, King Qin chose some good snow ginseng
然后，秦王挑选了一些 上好的雪参
and asked me to take it to the palace to give to Madame.
并嘱咐我带去皇宫 献给夫人。
Convey my thanks to King Qin.
转达对秦王的谢意。
Madam, there is no need to hesitate.
女士，您无需犹豫。
Some time ago,
前一段时间，
I heard Miss say that you are from the Cui Family Army.
我听小姐说 你是崔家军的人。
At the request of King Qin,
应秦王的请求，
You continue to stay in the palace to look after me.
你就继续留在宫里 照顾我吧。
I've really caused trouble for Miss.
我真是给小姐添麻烦了。
No.
不。
Madam is too shy.
夫人太害羞了。
Talking about caring,
说到关怀，
Aunt Jin and the court ladies did it.
金姨妈和宫女们 就这么做了。
I just came here and accompanied Madam to chat.
我刚来这里 陪夫人聊天。
Miss is King Qin's heartthrob, right?
小姐是秦王的心上人吧？
Despite never having met King Qin,
尽管从未见过秦王，
I once sent a secret letter to him
我曾经 给他寄过一封密信
in my most difficult situation.
在我最困难的情况下。
The character can be seen from various details.
从各种细节就能看出性格。
I know he has no female relatives in his residence.
据我所知，他的住处没有女性亲戚。
You must be his idol
你一定是他的偶像
so that he can calmly entrust me to you.
这样他就能平静地 将我托付给你。
Madam is truly very perceptive.
夫人真是太有洞察力了。
I am a person
我是一个人
unfaithful and immoral.
不忠且不道德。
Only death
只有死亡
that could end my life.
那可能会结束我的生命。
King Qin once promised me that time
秦王 当年曾答应过我
he will help me find the Emperor's First Grandson.
他会帮我找到 皇长孙的。
I know King Qin
我认识秦王
is a person who keeps promises.
是一个信守承诺的人。
My status is as the Previous Crown Princess.
我的身份是 前任太子妃。
Now in the palace, my situation is very awkward and I don't feel free.
现在在皇宫里，我的处境 很尴尬，没有自由的感觉。
I want to leave the palace,
我想离开皇宫
go to a remote place,
去一个偏僻的地方，
and settle somewhere.
并在某处定居。
Please Miss inform King Qin
请小姐转告秦王
to grant my wish.
来实现我的愿望。
Don't worry, madam.
别担心，女士。
King Qin will definitely agree to arrange it.
秦王肯定会同意 安排的。
Are you really surnamed He?
你真的姓何吗？
Beautiful and appropriate.
美丽又合适。
It turns out you are also talented in flower arranging.
原来你 在插花方面也很有天赋。
King Qin came the other day.
那天秦王来了。
At first I wanted to ask you to come out to meet him.
起初我想请你出来 见见他。
However, after that I thought just forget it.
不过，后来我想还是算了吧。
Now is not the right time, there will still be many opportunities in the future.
现在还不是时候， 未来还有很多机会。
Correct.
正确的。
After returning to the capital,
回到首都后，
His Majesty gave rewards to all three teams.
国王陛下 对三支队伍都给予了奖励。
However, only King Qin was not rewarded with anything.
然而，只有秦王 没有得到任何奖励。
I think there must be bad people on His Majesty's side.
我想，陛下那边肯定有坏人。
Most likely,
最有可能的，
He believed the slander he heard.
他相信了他所听到的诽谤 。
Things like this happen often.
像这样的事情经常发生。
His merits were so great that the Emperor felt threatened,
他的功绩如此之大 ，以至于皇帝感到受到威胁，
don't know what to reward.
不知道该奖励什么。
Possibly, this is also something that makes it difficult for His Majesty.
或许，这也是 让陛下为难的事情。
Actually,
实际上，
the status of the King of Qin was already the highest among the kings.
秦王的地位已经是 诸王之中最高的了。
However, King Qin was not rewarded at all despite his great contribution
然而，秦王 尽管做出了巨大的贡献，却没有得到任何奖励。
by reclaiming the two capitals and restoring the Yu Dynasty.
收复两都 ，恢复大禹王朝。
That's ridiculous.
这是荒谬的。
Do you think Dad...
你认为爸爸...
He is in his prime
他正值巅峰
and has no intention of appointing a Crown Prince at this time.
目前无意任命王储。
Otherwise, the one appointed must be King Qin.
否则， 指定的必定是秦王。
However, King Xin is the eldest son
然而辛王是长子
and King Qi was His Majesty's favorite son since childhood.
而齐王 从小就是皇帝陛下最宠爱的儿子。
Since ascending the throne, His Majesty has not appointed a queen.
自从登基以来， 陛下就没有任命过皇后。
The only son born to the empress was a legitimate son.
皇后所生的唯一的儿子 是嫡子。
Tomorrow, I plan to submit written suggestions,
明天我打算 提交书面建议，
request His Majesty
请求陛下
to bestow a posthumous title on King Qin's biological mother.
追谥 秦王的生母。
King Qin made such a great contribution, that's as it should be
秦王有这么大的贡献， 这是理所当然的
his biological mother was given the posthumous title of Empress.
其生母被追 谥为皇后。
Reportedly, King Qin's biological mother had a humble background.
据说，秦王的生母 出身卑微。
That is not important.
那并不重要。
She gave birth to King Qin, such an extraordinary son.
她生下了秦王， 这样一个非凡的儿子。
As his biological mother,
作为他的亲生母亲，
didn't she deserve to be given the posthumous title of Empress?
难道她不配被 追封为皇后吗？
(Istana Chaoqian)
(Istana Chaoqian)
I've decided.
我决定了。
Lady Dong, the biological mother of King Xin and King Qi,
董氏，辛王、齐王的生母，
given the posthumous title of Empress of Zhaocheng.
谥号 为昭成皇后。
Lady Liu, King Qin's biological mother,
刘氏，秦王的生母，
given the posthumous title of Consort Zhaoyi.
谥号 为昭仪妃。
- This...
- 这...
This is not correct.
这是不正确的。
His Majesty, according to the servant this is not accurate.
陛下，据仆人所说，这并不准确。
Servant agrees with Great General Pei.
奴婢同意裴大将军的话。
The posthumous title was given because it was a gift from His Majesty
谥号是 因为这是国王陛下赐予的礼物
and because of human ethical logic.
也因为人类的伦理逻辑。
After King Qin mobilized troops from the Laolan Border,
秦王 从老兰边境调集军队后，
he crushed the rebellion and retook two capitals.
他镇压了叛乱 ，夺回了两个首都。
With such a large contribution,
有了如此大的贡献，
if his biological mother had only been Concubine Zhaoyi,
如果他的生母 只是昭仪妃的话
fear that it will be difficult to show His Majesty's grace
怕难以展现 陛下的恩宠
that shines in all directions.
向四面八方闪耀。
His Majesty, according to the servant,
据仆人说，陛下，
Mistress Liu gave birth to the King of Qin
刘夫人生下秦王
should have been given the posthumous title of Empress.
死后应该追谥 皇后。
Servant agrees.
仆人同意了。
- Servant agrees.
- 仆人同意了。
All of you
你们所有人
said that King Qin made a great contribution to reclaiming the two capitals.
说秦王 为收复两都做出了巨大的贡献。
What about the eastern capital?
那么东都呢？
Do not be angry, Your Majesty.
请不要生气，陛下。
All because of the useless Ananda.
都是因为 阿难无用。
Shut up.
住口。
Mrs. Liu had a humble background.
刘夫人出身卑微。
Is it just because she is King Qin's biological mother,
难道只是因为她是 秦王的亲生母亲，
should she be given the posthumous title of Empress?
死后是否应该追封她 为皇后？
His Majesty, regarding the slave's biological mother from a simple background
陛下，从简单的背景来看奴隶的生母
so that His Majesty does not like,
以免陛下不喜欢，
request that the title of servant king be removed
要求取消仆人国王的头衔
and send servants to Laolan Border to guard the border.
并派仆从到老兰边境， 镇守边关。
- This...
- 这...
You...
你...
Do not be angry, Your Majesty.
请不要生气，陛下。
As a child, it is appropriate
作为一个孩子，这是合适的
King Qin was grateful to his biological mother who had given birth to him.
秦王很感激 生下他的生母。
Please forgive the King of Qin.
请秦王恕罪。
Get lost, get out of here!
迷路了，离开这里！
I don't want to see you , this disobedient child again!
我不想 再见到你这个不听话的孩子！
Get out!
出去！
He doesn't respect his father.
他不尊重他的父亲。
He has no respect for his father!
他根本不尊重他的父亲！
(A Virtuous Person Takes Great Responsibility)
（有德之人，责任重大）
His Majesty's verbal command.
陛下的口头命令。
Remembering that King Qin had spoken harshly,
想起秦王 曾经说过狠话，
insulted his father, and made a fuss at the palace meeting,
侮辱父亲， 在宫会上大惊小怪，
a special order was issued to remove King Qin
特下旨罢黜 秦王
from his position as chief military officer.
从他 担任首席军事长官的职位上。
He was ordered to introspect at the Qin King's Residence.
命他去秦王府反省。
He must obey orders,
他必须服从命令，
can't leave a single step from the house,
一步都不能离开家，
cannot participate in military affairs,
不能参与 军事事务，
and may not discuss government affairs unilaterally.
不得 单方面讨论政务。
That's all.
就这样。
Servant, Li Ni, is grateful for His Majesty's gift.
奴婢李妮 感激陛下的恩赐。
(Calm and Focused to Achieve Goals)
（冷静并专注 于实现目标）
When I was little, my nanny aunt said,
小时候， 保姆阿姨说：
If I have a wish, make a bamboo dragonfly.
如果我有一个愿望， 就做一只竹蜻蜓吧。
When he falls to the ground, my wish will come true.
当他倒在地上时， 我的愿望就实现了。
At that time, I really wanted to meet my mother.
那时 我真的很想见见我的妈妈。
Everyone else has a mother, only I don't have one.
别人都有妈妈， 唯独我没有。
So, I folded a lot of bamboo dragonflies.
于是，我折了 很多竹蜻蜓。
I climbed up the wall and took them down one by one.
我爬上墙 ，把它们一一取下来。
Until
直到
everything was removed then I knew
然后我就知道一切都被删除了
that my nanny aunt was just comforting me.
我的保姆阿姨 只是在安慰我。
No matter how much
无论多少
bamboo dragonfly that I made,
我做的竹蜻蜓，
This wish cannot be realized.
这个愿望无法实现。
♪When the ocean is no longer wide♪
♪当大海不再广阔♪
♪Are you still going to wait♪
♪你还要等吗♪
Give it back.
放回去。
Lowly child!
卑微的孩子！
Bring it back!
把它带回来！
Your mother is the lowest of servants.
你的母亲是最低等的仆人。
You made him die as soon as he was born.
他一出生你就让他死了。
Bring it back!
把它带回来！
♪Will you still remember♪
♪你还记得吗♪
♪Still miss this hometown♪
♪还是很想念这个故乡♪
Enough already.
已经足够。
Say,
说，
Why did you steal your sister's things?
你为什么偷你姐姐的东西？
I didn't take the item.
我没有拿走该物品。
He was the one who took my bamboo dragonfly and called me names.
他就是那个夺走我的竹蜻蜓 并辱骂我的人。
What did he call you?
他叫你什么？
Try to say.
尝试说一下。
You can't say that, can you?
你不能这么说，是吗？
You actually dare to lie?
你居然还敢撒谎？
I do not lie.
我不撒谎。
You're still arguing!
你们还吵架！
I do not lie!
我不撒谎！
You are indeed lying!
你确实在撒谎！
You're still arguing!
你们还吵架！
I am not lying!
我没有说谎！
- You are lying! - I do not lie!
- 你在说谎！ - 我不撒谎！
Watch out you argue again!
小心你们又吵架了！
I am not lying!
我没有说谎！
You are indeed lying!
你确实在撒谎！
- You are lying! - I do not lie!
- 你在说谎！ - 我不撒谎！
You are lying!
你在说谎！
I do not lie!
我不撒谎！
♪Maybe you'll also think about it once in a while♪
♪也许你也会 偶尔想一想♪
(Calm and Focused to Achieve Goals)
（冷静并专注 于实现目标）
When I was little,
我小时候，
(Liu Chengfeng's grave) you once saved my life.
（刘乘风坟墓） 你曾经救过我的命。
Then, you come home.
然后，你就回家了。
No matter what I do,
不管我做什么，
you support me silently.
你默默支持我。
When I make a mistake,
当我犯错时，
You are also the one who helped me bear it.
你也是帮我承受的人。
By using my name,
通过使用我的名字，
I don't know how many dangers you have gone through.
我不知道你经历了多少危险。
Eventually,
最终，
You also died saving me.
你也为了救我而死。
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
You have been my son for more than ten years.
你当我儿子 已经十多年了。
This,
这，
I erected this monument for you
我为你立了这座纪念碑
so that your real name can be revealed to the world.
以便您的真实姓名 可以向全世界公开。
However, in my father's heart,
然而，在父亲心里，
You are always like my real son.
你永远都像我的亲生儿子一样。
Feng'er,
Feng'er,
Ayah
阿亚
will definitely avenge you.
一定会为你报仇的。
From now on,
今后，
you're just you,
你就是你，
is no longer Cui Lin.
不再是崔琳了。
You are Liu Chengfeng.
You are Liu Chengfeng.
However, you will forever be Dad's son.
但是，你永远 是爸爸的儿子。
You will always be my brother too.
你也永远是我的兄弟。
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
Young Master.
少爷。
(Kuil Qingyun)
(Kuil Qingyun)
I never considered both of us as employer and servant
我从来没有把 我们当成雇主和仆人
could leave the royal palace alive.
才能活着离开皇宫 。
Look,
看，
the residence that King Qin arranged for you is very quiet.
秦王 给你安排的住处很安静。
After all, there must be great blessings after escaping a great disaster.
毕竟 躲过大劫之后，必定有大福报。
You still have to fetch the Emperor's First Grandson back.
还得把 皇帝长孙接回来。
You will be happy and live long.
你会幸福 并且长寿。
(Residence of the King of Qin) There are 18 bends in the Laolan River,
（秦王府） 老兰河有十八湾，
the first bend is a shallow pine tree,
第一个弯是 一棵浅松树，
fish in the shallows of the pine trees
松树浅滩里的鱼
- fat-fat, - Eat meat, Shiqi.
- 胖胖， - 吃肉，十七。
not as beautiful as the girl's eyes.
没有女孩的眼睛那么美丽。
- Laolan. - Shiqi.
- Laolan. - Shiqi.
Come on, get the wine.
来吧，拿酒来。
Third Sister, Fourth Sister!
三姐，四姐！
Can!
能！
There are 18 bends in the Laolan River.
老兰河有十八个弯。
Spend it.
花掉它。
Cheers!
干杯!
Let's spend it!
让我们花吧！
♪There are 18 bends in the Laolan River♪
♪老兰河有十八个弯♪
♪The first bend is a shallow pine tree♪
♪第一个弯是 一棵浅松树♪
♪Ada 18...♪
♪艾达 18...♪
- Young General Pei.
——年轻的裴将军。
Give a portion of lamb to Young General Pei.
给裴少将一份羊肉。
Good!
好的！
Try this lamb steak.
尝尝这道羊排。
Come on, give some meat to Young General Pei.
来，给 裴少将军吃点肉吧。
Try our lamb steak.
尝尝我们的羊排。
- Come on, one more. - Eat this.
- 来吧，再来一张。 - 吃这个。
Mari.
马里。
Young General Pei,
年轻的裴将军，
this meat is delicious.
这肉很好吃。
Let's drink.
我们喝吧。
Come on, continue drinking.
来吧，继续喝。
Continue.
继续。
- Shiqi, - Good wine.
- Shiqi, - Good wine.
Come on, one more.
来吧，再来一张。
the situation is like this.
情况是这样的。
Maybe you drink wine?
也许你喝葡萄酒？
grilling meat, and singing here?
在这里烤肉， 唱歌？
Drink a glass first.
先喝一杯。
Is it ripe yet?
成熟了吗？
Drink a glass.
喝一杯。
Did you know that
你知道吗
troops sent by Sun Jing towards Baiyue...
孙敬派兵 前往百越……
Taste whether this lamb is delicious or not,
尝尝这羊肉 好吃不好吃，
look at the results of the grill this time.
看看这次烧烤的结果。
Sit down.
坐下。
Let's drink.
我们喝吧。
Mari.
马里。
There are King Xin's spies outside.
外面有辛王的探子。
- Lower your voice when talking. - Fulfill it.
- 说话时放低声音。 - 实现它。
I've been waiting for you for the past few days.
这几天我一直在等你。
Although at this time Sun Jing
虽然此时的孙静
poisoned and unconscious at Tong Border,
在塘边中毒昏迷，
he will come to his senses sooner or later.
他迟早会醒悟的。
The troops he sent towards Baiyue were already on their way back.
他派往百越的部队 已经在返回的路上了。
If those troops gathered with Sun Jing at the Tong Border,
如果那些军队 与孙敬聚集在潼边，
that would be troublesome.
那可就麻烦了。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
so what do you mean?
所以你是什么意思？
I've been pondering for the past few days.
这几天我一直在思考。
The best way is
最好的办法是
think of a way to get Grand General Pei to send you to Changzhou.
想办法让裴大将军 送你去常州。
Here is Changzhou.
这里是常州。
Here is the Han River.
这里是汉江。
From south to north,
从南到北，
here
这里
is the best place to intercept and kill the Baiyue expeditionary army.
是拦截杀百越远征军的最佳地点。
Stay cool,
保持冷静，
My father and I will definitely sort this out.
我和我父亲一定会 解决这个问题的。
There is one more thing that needs your help.
还有一件事需要你的帮助。
I will go to any lengths to deal with your problems.
我会尽一切努力 来解决你的问题。
No need to run into danger.
无需遇到危险。
You just have to help me with this.
你只需要帮我解决这个问题。
Stay cool.
保持冷静。
Is there a verbal message from King Qin?
有秦王的口信吗？
Then, thank you for delivering the letter.
那么，谢谢你 送来这封信。
Would Commander He not read it?
何司令 不看吗？
It turned out to be Young General Pei
原来是裴少将军
who came in person to deliver King Qin's letter.
亲自来 送秦王的信。
Please deliver this letter to Commander He.
请将此信转交给 何司令。
No, you also know that she is now Miss Cui.
不，你也知道 ，她现在是崔小姐了。
He was outside Luoyang City, at the Cui Family Army headquarters.
他现在在洛阳城外， 崔家军总部。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
You have important things to discuss with the Cui Family Army
你有重要的事情要 和崔家军商量
Or have you found a way to retake the eastern capital?
还是找到了夺回东都的办法？
Not both.
不是都。
This is a personal thing.
这是个人的事情。
Despite this enormous Qin King's Residence
尽管秦王府如此庞大
was surrounded by the Yulin Team very tightly
被榆林队围 得很严实
by order of His Majesty,
奉陛下之命，
I can't believe you couldn't find anyone to deliver the mail.
我不敢相信你找不到 人来送邮件。
What about Erduo?
尔多呢？
You may not know that now the Yulin Army is commanded
你可能不知道，现在 指挥的是榆林军
to give tasks to the people in the residence every day.
每天给住所里的人布置任务。
No matter how great Erduo is,
无论二多多么伟大，
he wouldn't be able to go and come home in a day.
他一天之内​​都无法回家。
Shiqi, I told you the Cui Family now...
十七， 我现在就告诉你崔家的事了……
Who said earlier that he was willing to go through danger without hesitation?
先前是谁说愿意 冒着危险义无反顾的？
You changed your mind so quickly?
你这么快就改变主意了？
Also this box. This is a newly purchased snack.
还有这个盒子。 这是新买的零食。
You deliver it, this is his favorite food.
你送过来，这是他最喜欢的食物。
Hurry up.
赶快。
(Tang Cake Shop)
(唐饼店)
Shiqi is now locked up at home,
世奇现在被关在家中，
but he always remembers to write you a letter.
但他总是记得 给你写信。
You really won't read that letter?
你真的不 看那封信吗？
Don't worry, Young General Pei.
裴少将军放心。
Even if all the bad people in this world perish,
就算这个世界上的坏人都 灭亡，
King Qin will definitely be fine.
秦王一定会没事的。
His Majesty saved your life many times despite the risks,
陛下多次 冒着风险救了你的命，
but you don't care at all.
但你根本不在乎。
It seems,
它似乎，
you really have a heart of stone.
你真是铁石心肠。
The King of Qin did a great job this time.
秦王这次干得不错。
If he remains in government, what reward can His Majesty give?
如果他继续执政， 陛下能给予什么奖励呢？
If His Majesty does not reward him,
如果陛下不赏赐他，
whether his two older brothers, King Qin and officials in the government
无论是他的两个哥哥秦王 还是朝廷官员
will be afraid?
会害怕吗？
The King of Qin left angrily and was locked up.
秦王愤然离去 ，被关了起来。
On the surface, his military powers appeared to be revoked.
从表面上看， 他的军事权力似乎被撤销了。
But actually,
但实际上，
had he really lost the Western Border Army?
他真的失去了 西边军吗？
Young General Pei is also the one who leads the army to war,
裴少将也是 率军打仗的人，
should know when to attack, when to camp and rest,
应该知道什么时候进攻， 什么时候扎营和休息，
the principle is the same.
原理是一样的。
It's late.
现在已经晚了。
Young General Pei was not free to remain in the Cui Family Army.
裴少将没有自由 留在崔家军。
I won't take you.
我不会带你去。
Until found.
直到被发现。
It wasn't Erduo who delivered the letter.
送信的不是尔多。
Some are very disappointed, right?
有些人很失望，对吧？
No.
不。
You must be hungry at this time of night, right?
大晚上的这个时候你一定很饿吧？
Eat freshly delivered snacks.
吃新鲜送来的零食。
You're the best. I'm a little hungry.
你是最好的。 我有点饿了。
Eat it.
吃了它。
Commander, this snack is not too sweet and will make you feel bad,
指挥官，这个点心 不太甜，会让你不舒服的，
really very delicious.
真的非常好吃。
You really won't read that letter?
你真的不 看那封信吗？
How about you read it?
你读一下怎么样？
(Tang Cake Shop)
(唐饼店)
Why is there only blank paper?
为什么只有一张白纸？
Commander, you expected that, didn't you?
指挥官，你也预料到了这一点吧？
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Li Ni asks Pei Yuan to deliver the letter.
李妮请裴渊 送信。
That means even though he is locked up,
这意味着即使他被关起来，
there were still people he could use.
还有他可以利用的人。
Apart from that, the Western Border Army also continued to listen to his orders.
除此之外，西边军 也继续听他的命令。
Anything else doesn't matter.
其他什么都不重要。
Why waste ink?
为什么要浪费墨水？
You two smart people always go back and forth like this,
你们两个聪明人 总是这样来回走动，
aren't you tired?
你不累吗？
Correct.
正确的。
Unlike certain people who just need to blow the whistle,
与某些只需要举报的人不同，
then Erduo will immediately rush over.
然后二多就会立刻 冲过去。
♪If you forget the fire of love you once had♪
♪如果你忘记了曾经拥有的爱情之火♪
♪Memories will be destroyed and drowned♪
♪记忆将会被摧毁并淹没♪
♪Your heart is full of color♪
♪你的心充满色彩♪
♪Makes it hard for me to forget our relationship♪
♪让我很难忘记 我们的关系♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪如果渴望 不被遗忘的话♪
♪Hoping to return to the first time we met♪
♪希望能回到 我们第一次见面的时候♪
♪The destined warmth I want to leave you♪
♪命中注定的温暖 我想离开你♪
♪If love can remember we once promised♪
♪如果爱能记得 我们曾经的约定♪
♪Even though this love hurts me, I will still live for you♪
♪即使这份爱让我受伤， 我仍会为你而活♪
♪Pulling out the limits of memory, waiting is the hardness of my heart♪
♪拉出记忆的极限， 等待是我心的坚硬♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪如果爱能记得我们的约定♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪逆转业力， 不后悔曾经爱过你♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪我愿意把我的心交给你 ，等待你的答复♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪如果爱能记得我们的约定♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪逆转业力， 不后悔曾经爱过你♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪我愿意把我的心交给你 ，等待你的答复♪